If you're the one doing the reporting,
إذا كنت أنت المختص بإعداد التقارير،
here are some of my personal guidelines when analyzing data.
ها هي بعض الإرشادات عند تحليل البيانات.
First, plot your data.
أولاً، ضع بياناتك في مخطط.
Second, if you have outliers,
ثانيًا، إذا كان لديك عناصر داخلية،
determine how you should handle them.
حدد كيف ستتعامل معها.
This might require a domain expert of the field.
قد يتطلب ذلك خبير نطاق للحقل.
Should you remove them?
هل يجب إزالتهم؟
Should you fix them? Should you keep them?
هل يجب إصلاحهم؟ هل يجب إبقائهم؟
Third, if you're working with data that are normally distributed,
ثالثًا، إذا كنت تعمل على بيانات موزعة بشكل طبيعي،
the bell shape that we saw before,
شكل الجرس الذي رأيناه من قبل،
you can find out every little detail about
يمكنك اكتشاف كل التفاصيل الصغيرة حول
the data with only the mean and the standard deviation.
البيانات بالانحراف المعياري والمتوسط فقط.
This may seem surprising but it's true.
قد يبدو ذلك مفاجئًا لكنه حقيقيًا.
However, if our data are skewed,
على الرغم من ذلك، إذا كانت البيانات منحرفة،
the five-number summary provides much more information for
يقدم ملخص الخمس أرقام معلومات أكثر
these data sets than the mean and the standard deviation can provide.
لمجموعات البيانات هذه أكثر من التي يقدمها الانحراف المعياري والمتوسط.
Again, the most useful and informative summary you can get is frequently a visual.
مرة أخرى، أكثر ملخص مفيد ومعلوماتي يمكنك الحصول عليه غالبًا ما يكون بصريًا.
In upcoming lessons, we will focus
في الدروس القادمة، سنركز على
specifically on the visuals that will best convey our message.
البصريات تحديدًا التي ستوصل رسالتنا بأفضل طريقة.